Email: david.j.bramwell@googlemail.com

Website: <a href="https://dbramwell.github.io/">https://dbramwell.github.io/</a>

### DAVID BRAMLER

## Summary

A seasoned senior software engineer with a wide range of experience, having had roles in Dev OPS and QA automation as well as pure development. A collaborative team player, well versed in mentoring junior members of the team, making architectural decisions and increasing release cadence.

Currently working with Python and Javascript, with past commercial experience using Ruby, Java, Groovy, PHP and others, as well as lots of exposure to various Linux flavours and bash scripting.

An advocate for infrastructure as code, automated testing and release pipelines. Experienced across many infrastructure stacks, from barebones servers to serverless. Previously passed AWS developer certification with experience across many AWS services.

Spare time often includes trying out new tech and contributing to open source. A list of my open source contributions can be found at <a href="https://dbramwell.github.io">https://dbramwell.github.io</a>.

## **Previous Employment**

#### Sponge - Senior Software Developer (September 2020 - Current)

Django, VUE, Terraform, Kubernetes, GCP, CDK, AWS, Docker, GitHub Actions, PSQL

Lead developer of Sponge's flagship SAAS Learning Management System. Responsible for making architectural and design decisions, mentoring and upskilling other members of the team and making individual contributions to the codebase.

- Led a team of 4 developers in tackling technical debt, upgrading the system from Django 1.6 and Python 2.7 to Django 4.2 and Python 3.10.
- Led a team of 3 developers in adding unit and E2E tests.
- Redesigned the SDLC to include automated testing and ephemeral environments for product sign off.
- Leading development of an async REST api along with api driven, static VUE frontend.
- Tackled scaling issues from how we horizontally scale our GCP and AWS infrastructure to optimizing individual ORM generated database queries for large datasets in our Postgres database.
- Increased release frequency from once every two months to multiple times per week.
- Collaborated with the product function to design and develop new features to enable our clients to better manage their training.

#### **Endemol Shine Group - Technical Lead (June 2018 - September 2020)**

Javascript, Typescript, ReactJS, PHP, AWS, CDK, Amplify, Cypress, FFMPEG, MYSQL, Docker

Lead developer of a Training Platform as well as a key developer on Endemol's Media Asset Management (MAM) system, both utilizing a large number of serverless and server based AWS services. Responsible for key architecture decisions and mentoring newer members of the team. Instilled best practices such as code reviews, automated testing and infrastructure as code into the development lifecycle of all applications.

#### Comprehensive Care - Full Stack Developer (June 2017 - December 2017)

Javascript, Ruby on Rails, Angularjs, Jenkins, MS SQL

6 month contract while on a 2 year backpacking trip. Lead developer of an asthma treatment recommendation application, built on Rails and Angularjs. Ran workgroups on best practices and championed addition of unit tests and automated deployments across all applications.

#### **UBS Investment Bank – Developer (February 2016 - July 2016)**

Javascript, BackboneJS, Grails, Java, Groovy, Gradle, Maven, Teamcity, Oracle SQL

Working across a suite of 10 Java applications and 1 Grails application as well as maintaining and improving the CI pipeline.

#### UBS Investment Bank - Dev-Ops Engineer (April 2013 - February 2016)

Gradle, Maven, Java, Groovy, Teamcity, Bash, RHEL, Javascript, Oracle SQL

Part of a 5 person team responsible for providing developer enablement for around 80 developers and automating the build and deployment processes of 10 applications.

#### Betfair - QA automation engineer (November 2011 - March 2013)

Groovy, Java, Selenium Webdriver, Maven, Jenkins

Responsible for automating the manual test library.

# Qualifications

- BSc (Hons) Degree in Mathematics from Nottingham University
- A-Levels:
  - Maths A
  - Further Maths A
  - Chemistry C
- GCSEs: 11 A\* to C